JAMES BETANCOURT

Phone: +57 (350) 856 2509 Email: james.92b11@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated electronics engineer with up to 6 years of experience working with electronics Circuits, telecommunications, computer systems and cybersecurity. Looking for a company to utilize my experience and project management skills, Ability to work under pressure to meet project deadlines. A good team player with a passion to grow professionally that will allow me to apply and expand the skills and knowledge that I have gained throughout my career.

LANGUAGES: Spanish & English.

EDUCATION

- Google IT Support Currently Studying.
- Master's degree, Project Management 2021.
- BS, Electronic Engineering 2019.
- Industrial Electrical Technologist 2012.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUTHERLAND GLOBAL | December 2023 - Currently

- Integration, implementation and adoption of new technologies to optimize the performance and efficiency of IT environments.
- Administration of re-imagined machines using AD, GPO's, SCCM, JAMF PRO, VPN's, Scripts, among others.
- Network and server management.
- Technical troubleshooting.
- Information security.
- Auditing massive deployments for campaigns.

BTP METERS AND ACCESSORIES | December 2022 - July 2023

- Oversee large projects of 4 cities provided services for up to 6,000 households.
- Analyzed of Architectural blueprints, specifications, and field reports.
- Developed, executed, and maintained strategic plans with the field team, addressing current field conditions to complete project in a timely manner.
- Verified, chronological validation and processing of data to prepare financial and technical reports.
- Drove efficiency and optimized inventory control procedures to reduce lead times.
- Diagnosis of equipment to assure the correct performance.
- Deploy programs and applications to automate and improve the efficiency processes.
- Field team training for each project on the correct use of applications and electronic components.

WODEN S.A.S | March 2020 - December 2022

- Develop key process to restore and refurbish of high value electronic equipment on the field of telecommunications.
- Elaborated preventive and corrective maintenance of equipment focused on analog and digital data transmission.
- Implemented scheduling changes that helped to continuous improvement of production goals.
- Coordinated and trained up to 3 people on the external network area, 2 people on the BTB area, 4 people on the mobile network area and 6 people on the equipment maintenance.
- Supported teams from different areas of the company.

SKILLS

- Project Management.
- Read and Interpretation of Blueprints (Electronic and Electrical).
- Àdapt new concepts quickly while working Under pressure.
- Document Management.
- Strong work ethic and team working skills.
- Personal Development.
- Computer Skills.
- PCB Interpretation, soldering and Testing.
- Sales skills.
- Flexibility.
- Prompt Crafting.

PROFESIONAL CERTIFICATION

- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking (Google 2024).
- Technical Support Fundamentals (Google 2024).
- Business models (2022)
- Introduction to Java SE (2022).
- Basic cooperativeness (2014).
- Process development oral and written communications in English applied in contexts specific (2013).
- Calculation of costs of production (2012)
 Modelling 3D with Catia v5 (2012).
- Personal growth and social interaction (2012)
- Market study (2012).
- Prevention and solution of conflicts (2012)
- Human relations and corporate interactions (2012).
- Drawing of entities and plans in two dimensions in AutoCAD (2011).

PROGRAMS

- Operational System's: MacOs, Windows and Kali Linux.
- Suite Office: Word, Excel, Power Point.
- Suite iWork: Pages, Numbers, Keynote.
- Active Directory, Group Policy Management, DHCP, SCCM, Laps UI, MainApp and Web Filters.
- Electronic Platforms: Proteus, Arduino, Pic C, DSCH3, Simuproc, Microwind31.
- Programming Languages: Visual Studio Code, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML, PHP, Phyton, C++, C# and JAVA.
- Git and GltHub.
- Virtual Box and Virtual Machines.
- Cisco Packtet Tracer (CCNA1 & CCNA2).
- Sentinel One, Thousand Eyes, AWS.
- JAMF PRO.

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Lifeguard and swimming lessons for low-income kids - Comfatolima Sport Club.
- Volunteering at a Senior Home" Jardín de los Abuelos" Residential Community.